JULIET KERN

UW Biomedical Engineering Student

https://j2kern.github.io/

(647) 504 3442

ĭ2kern@uwaterloo.ca

http://www.linkedin.com/in/julietkern

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Development | HTML, CSS, JS, C#, C++, Matlab

Tools | React, Angular, NodeJS, Visual Studio Code, Git, Bootstrap

UI/UX & Design | Photoshop, AdobeXD, Axure, Figma

CAD | Solidworks, Rapid Prototyping, 3D Printing

Product Dev | Agile and Iterative design, User research, User testing

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

Sept 2019 - Present

BASc For Biomedical Engineering

ST. ALOYSIUS GONZAGA

2015 - 2019

Science Award | Top graduating student in Science (extracurricular involvement)

INTERESTS

Oil Painting, Photography, Old Videography and VHS, Zines, Outdoors and Adventure

WORK EXPERIENCE

FRONT END DEVELOPER & UI/UX DESIGNER

The Home Depot | May 2020 - Aug. 2020

Canada Technology | Designed and developed a webpage for Home Depot's internal employee website for the IT department. The page displayed an informational map of the head office, prototyped with **Axure** and **Photoshop**, and developed in **Angular** with an integrated Google Maps **API**.

Pro Store Walk Portal | Worked alongside a team to develop a **heat map** of the Home Depot store departments in **Angular** to **visualize** trends in sales and pinpoint opportunities for company growth. Deployed across all of the **182** Canadian Home Depot stores.

LAB ASSISTANT

York University | July 2018 - Aug. 2018

Collected electromyography data using electrodes, **processed** the information using **Matlab** and submitted **technical reports** to the bioelectrical engineering professor for his research on smart clothing.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

MEMORY MAPS

Hackathon project | Jan. 2020

Successfully **developed** the **front-end** of a website using **HTML**, **CSS**, and Google Cloud's **Geolocation API** that focuses on preventing people with neurological disorders such as Dementia or Alzheimer's from getting lost.

Collaborated with team members under **high pressure** and **short time** constraint to complete the project **efficiently**.

BIOMECHATRONICS DESIGN TEAM LEAD

University of Waterloo | Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2020

Led a team of 12 to develop a sustainable powered arm prosthetic for a double amputee in El Salvador in need of device.

Files modified in Solidworks, 3D Printed and varnished for comfort.

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

STEM 50/50 PRESIDENT AND FOUNDER

St. Aloysius Gonzaga | 2018 - 2019

Provided students with fun learning opportunities, a chance to explore their interests and a platform to advocate for a more **diverse future** in STEM careers, with **over 100 applications** after our first meeting.